Guide to the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale records
1980-2002
RU 1059
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
The materials consist of newsclippings, posters, meeting minutes, and ephemera documenting events and activities of the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale.
Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Larry Kramer Initiative for Lesbian and Gay Studies, 2004, and from the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale, 2009.
Custodial History
Posters in this collection were transferred from the Exhibit Materials from The Pink and The Blue, Larry Kramer Initiative for Lesbian and Gay Studies, Yale University (RU 963)
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Arrangement
The records are arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
In 1969, students founded the first gay organization at Yale, now called the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale (LGBT Co-op). The LGBT Co-op is an "action organization whose purpose is to foster and encourage an environment at Yale in which all queer and LGBT identified people can express themselves academically, artistically, socially, and politically." The Co-op sponsors social and educational events and activities, including Pride Week every spring.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of newsclippings, posters, meeting minutes, and ephemera documenting events and activities of the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale.
Bisexuality; College students; Gay college students; Homosexuality; Lesbianism; Transsexualism; Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale; Yale University -- Students
- LGBT Co-op records, 1980-2002; Accession 2005-A-201
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 4 contains personal student information and is restricted as established by Yale Corporation regulations. Expiration dates of restrictions are indicated at the file level.
  - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2058 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2061 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 10)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2062 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2063 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2064 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13-17)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2065 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18-21)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2066 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2067 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2068 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26-29)
  - 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2070 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Restricted materials (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Student files are restricted until January 1, 2071 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Posters, circa 1984-2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Oversize, circa 1984-2002 (Box 5)
- LGBT Co-op records, circa 1980s-2009; Accession 2009-A-194
  Materials in Box 1 are restricted until January 1, 2041 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Gay Alliance at Yale and Gay Student Center, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gay Student Center newsletter, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gay and Lesbian Coop, circa 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1980s-2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale conference, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photograph fo BGLAD Awareness Day, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Events, calendars, flyers, posters, 1980s-2008 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - Oversize, 2006, 2009 (Box 3)
  - Yale University Pink Book, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980s-2005 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Intercollegiate lesbian and gay groups, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Non-Yale lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender groups, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 13)